And so even the one who it comes from us.
And Father, I just pray that today that you need the proper to open and you need to ask
you to let you guide us.
Father, you pray that you can ask the right and you can do the right.
And I pray that all the ones you find in you.
Thank you, Jesus.
I think it's all right.
We're good?
Okay, cool.
Well, for those of you who haven't met me yet or don't know who I am, my name is Ryan.
I am one of the pastors here, and I am so grateful to be here this morning.
I'm excited about what God's doing.
A lot of you aren't aware of this, but there were 90-plus children in here last night covered
in SOCs, treating each other with nurse dogs.
It was at all.
And now there's one child in the room this morning.
No, but we're so blessed in our pastor and ourselves.
Super thankful for all this you did to put that together.
And all of you that stayed away to make this place look like church again was really awesome.
And, man, look, our worship team is crushing it.
Donovan, thank you so much.
And then I don't know about you, but my heart is so blessed to hear faithful sister in Christ
read the passage of Scripture that pretty much preaches itself.
So, worst case scenario, you guys got something out of that.
Hey, before we jump into our message this morning, let me recap where we've been and also where
we're headed, and then we'll get into the specifics of the message.
We've been in a series that we've called All In at the beginning of the year.
It's really about stewardship.
It's about asking ourselves, are we really all in in different areas of our life when it
comes to our relationship with Jesus?
And this week, actually, the last message of that series was to ask ourselves, are we
all in with our finances?
Are we all in with our physical bodies?
Are we all in with our souls?
We talked about forgiveness, and are we holding on to bitterness or anger or fear or grudges?
And we talked about last week, authentic, biblical community.
Are we all in with our relationships with one another?
And today, we're going to end by asking ourselves, are we all in with our neighbors?
Are we all in when it comes to fearing our faith in Jesus with those that are around us?
Let's now wrap up this series, and then you have a few paper somewhere near you, a packet
of paper on your seats.
This is for the next series that we are starting next week.
So, just some housekeeping.
I want you to take this home.
Don't do it now, because then you'll be distressing.
You won't listen to me, and I said, take this home and do it sometime throughout the week.
We'll also be sending instructions online this week as well.
But our next series is going to be going over the spiritual type, the spiritual personality
type, almost like a personality exam, but for your spiritual life.
How do you naturally connect with God?
I'm really excited about this series.
It is going to be strange.
I'm just going to be honest with you.
Honesty is good.
It's going to be strange.
It's going to, of course, a lot of us out of our comfort zone.
It's probably going to push me out of my comfort zone.
Because what happens is we tend to connect with God one or maybe two ways, and we think
that that's how everybody should connect with God.
But God is, like, much bigger than that, and God uses all kinds of different ways to connect
with us.
And so what we're going to do is we're going to advance in these six ways that we connect
with God as individuals.
And you're going to be really pumped on the Sunday that we do the way that you connect with
God.
So one out of six Sundays you're going to love, and the other ones you're going to be like,
this is weird.
I don't like it.
And it's going to be great, because what's going to happen, hopefully, is we're going
to learn that we're going to be able to connect with God when we step out of our comfort zone
and try some things.
But the thing that I'm most excited about this year is this last week I talked a lot about
echo families.
And what tends to happen is we tend to be telling those people that connect with God the same
way that we connect with God.
And then we tend to get judgmental about people that connect with God in different ways than
we connect with God.
And so I hope, I hope that this series helps us to understand better our brothers and sisters
in Christ that might fall in different denominational streams than we do because they connect with
God a little bit different.
And that we here at Campus Community Church will be a church that pushes past some of that.
That we're able to have unity in the midst of a diverse culture of different theological
backgrounds.
Does that sound like for all I'm going to be terrifying in all the same terms?
All right.
So take that seed, pump them, fill it out, and it won't make sense to you until next week.
And that's going to make it all make sense for us next week.
Got it?
Cool.
Let's press.
Father, I thank you so much for this opportunity that I have to share your words this morning.
I pray, Holy Spirit, that you would show this place, that you would speak through your
words to us, that we would hear exactly what you want us to hear this morning.
And Peter preached the first New Testament.
And it was translated into the highlights of everyone in the room.
We all speak the same language this morning.
God, but I pray that this message would be translated into the hearts of each individual in the room.
That they would hear exactly what you want them to hear and nothing else.
For your glory and for our glory, in Jesus' name I pray.
Amen.
And that's chapter 1, verse 8.
Jesus said, but you, through his disciples, you will receive power when the Holy Spirit comes
upon you, and you will be my witnesses.
Tell me, people, about me everywhere.
In Jerusalem, throughout Judea, in Samaria, and to the ends of Syria.
Now, I don't know about you, but I'm assuming that this concept, this idea, when you found
out that we're going to be talking about personal evangelism, about hearing the gospel with
our friends or family members, that maybe you already started to get a bit uneasy.
Maybe you're already formulating an argument in the back of your mind for why this message
is for somebody else in my life for you.
And I get it.
I get it.
I can't tell you the amount of times that I've met new people, struck up a good conversation
with somebody at the golf course or with somebody at the cigar shop or at the grocery store.
You meet people, right?
And you get these good conversations going, and then the dreaded question for me sometimes
comes out.
You know, when it's coming, somebody's like, hey, what do you do for a living?
And it's a dreaded question because it really, for me, is in the 50s, 50s, it's about ourselves,
right?
Like, yeah, I'm a pastor.
And you might oftentimes think, oh, no way.
That's awesome.
Like, great.
You're a closer guy.
Cool.
A lot of times it's like, oh, can we, how can I get out of this conversation as quickly
as possible, right?
And most of us have probably had encounters like this with our friends or co-workers or
random strangers that we meet in the middle of the road, and the conversation comes through
our face, and things can get a little bit uncomfortable at times.
And it's just the reality that we have opposition in our culture when it comes to sharing our
face.
There's spiritual opposition.
We have an enemy.
Sadie does not want people to know about Jesus.
He wants to keep them in their brokenness and in their lostness.
He wants them to feel content where they are apart from Jesus.
We have a spiritual opposition.
There's cultural opposition.
Our culture is increasingly becoming more and more personal, which means, essentially,
we're moving from evidence-based truth to experience-based truth.
And so, what we all could use, we all used to be able to kind of get together on some
things and say, yes, this is objective truth, but now that's no longer the case.
It's like, well, that might be true for you.
That might work out for you, but it doesn't work for me.
And so, it's hard to share a message of Jesus, that Jesus says, I am the way, the truth,
and the right.
No one comes to the Father, but for me, it's hard to share that kind of a message in a
culture where people are like, yeah, maybe he's your way, and he's your truth, and he's
your life, but that's not going to work for me.
And we live in an increasingly post-Christian culture.
America used to be a predominantly Christian nation, and it was kind of just okay for us
to talk about faith and Jesus in the public square, but increasingly, it's becoming more
more and more of stuff.
So, we've got spiritual opposition, we've got cultural opposition, and most of us have
some personal opposition as well.
Fear is how we might be receiving them.
Fear that we don't have the right information and know all the answers to the questions that
they might ask us.
And not only that, but for those of you that grew up in the church, you've probably got some
fear around the models that were pushed upon you.
You're like, okay, Ronald, this is cool, but if you're asking me to walk on doors, or like
drag and crawl through the downtown walking model, I'm out, right?
And so, this is kind of my background.
This is the culture that I tune out of.
And so, I get it, I get the hesitancy, I get the, I myself have made many excuses and
messages like this for why I'm not going to do the thing that they're asking me to do,
because it's not going to work, or it's uncomfortable.
And with all of that opposition, the natural thing for us to do is to outsource this type
of thing to experts and extra girls.
So, you guys are like, hey, I'll bring my friends to church, Ryan, and you tell them about
Jesus.
Or, I'm introverted, and I'm uncomfortable with conversations, but like, my friends will
tell other people about Jesus.
Or, there's like this, there's a spiritual gift, you guys have heard of the spiritual
gift of evangelism?
And nobody has it.
But everybody is like, well, somebody else, right?
We make excuses.
We have spiritual opposition, cultural opposition, and personal opposition.
And yet, with all of that in the backdrop, Jesus tells us this, you will receive power when
the Holy Spirit comes upon you, and you will be my witnesses.
This is not a command primarily given to church leaders or the Hebrew extroverts, but it's
given to each one of us who have bowed our knees to Jesus, who have submitted our lives
to the lordship and leadership of Jesus.
As we've experienced the unconditional love and forgiveness of Jesus, it is our responsibility.
We have the privilege and the opportunity to be the witnesses to the people that are in our
life.
But, a gift of attention.
So, how do we do this in a thoughtful and engaging way in the midst of all of this opposition?
How do we learn to share Jesus in a way that doesn't come across as crazy, unloving, guilt-driven,
unloving, guilt-driven, or irrelevance?
How do we tell people about Jesus in a compelling way?
What better way than to look at a story where Jesus was telling somebody about Jesus, right?
So, we're going to go to John chapter 4.
If you have your Bibles, you're going to be a bouncer in John chapter 4.
I've had my illness here to read the entire passage.
We don't have time to read the entire passage.
I'm just going to pull out some points.
So, hopefully, you guys got the context, the best thought of this conversation that Jesus
had, you know, just to make a few more than that.
Well, let's talk here.
In verse 4, John chapter 4, verse 4, it says,
He, Jesus, had to go through Samaria on the way.
You're like, this is going to be a short sermon that you're going to stop and talk about
every single time, but here we go.
He had to go through Samaria on the way.
Here's my first kind of theological drawing-out point.
No, he didn't.
He didn't have to go through Samaria.
As a matter of fact, most Jewish men in that culture, in that day and age, would go out
of their way to not go through Samaria.
But this text says that Jesus had to go through Samaria.
I would argue that this is less of a geographical statement and more of a theological statement.
Jesus had to go through Samaria because he knew that he had a plan.
And he's a Messiah, so he's got some advantages on us.
But maybe not because it's just because it's better that Jesus goes through.
But we get the whole story.
So anyway, different stories are different days.
But Jesus knew that he had an appointed conversation with this woman.
And that he had an appointed testimony to the people of Samaria.
Jesus had to go through Samaria because he had a heart for this woman and he had a heart for these people.
And so if we're going to be a people that are going to stand on a stage with our neighbors,
coworkers, friends, we have to have a heart for them first.
We have to see the need that they have for the Messiah that we have experienced.
We see this even more in verse 13 and 14 when we see Jesus' heart for this woman.
I have to be asked for some water.
He says, anyone who drinks of this water will soon become thirsty again.
But those who drink the water that I give will never be thirsty again.
It becomes a fresh bubbling spring within them, giving them eternal life.
See, Jesus knows this woman's spiritual condition.
He knows she's thirsty.
He knows she needs a drink.
And he knows that he has a source of living water where she will never have to drink.
And you see how desperate she is for this.
He says, please, sir, give me this water.
I need this water.
And so if we're going to be a people that here are saved with our friends and family members,
our coworkers, our leaders, we have to start by having a question for them.
Seeing their need for Jesus.
Jesus knows that living in this culture, in this world, it's like this morning I was at my gym thing.
It's not a studio, which is really a good thing that says what I'm going to say.
And I don't want you guys to make fun of me.
The people that know about it are already making fun of me right now.
So anyway, so I'm running on the treadmill, right?
And we're doing sprint intervals and something.
And I'm in the midst of a sprint.
And I grab my water bottle.
And I take a big old gulp of water.
And guess what happens?
It feels amazing.
I didn't throw a lot.
It's not strong.
It feels amazing.
I'm like, man, you spread this water for my soul.
But guess what happens?
So he says, six later, I'm like, this is not good.
I might throw up or I might be fancy forever.
I'm not sure what's going to happen.
But Jesus uses this beautiful illustration to explain how people who don't have a relationship
with him in life, they get glimpses of the thing that's going to satisfy us.
Because creation is good.
God has put us in good tradition.
And apart from God, you can find presence of this world that satisfy us for some time.
But we know, those of us who have experienced Jesus know, that eventually it's all the way we need to drop.
There's a spirit inside of each and every single one of us that cannot be close with anything on this earth.
One of my favorite verses in the Old Testament to explain this text is a creature.
This idea is Ecclesiastes 3, verse 11.
Solomon says that God has placed eternity in each one of our hearts.
And so each one of your friends, family members, co-workers, neighbors, they have this eternal thirst for a relationship with God.
Whether they know it or not, whether they're willing to acknowledge it or not, they have a deep thirst for God.
And they can distrust themselves, they can find temporary satisfaction, they can find drinks of water that satisfy for today.
But a day is coming when whatever it is that they're putting their hope in, it's going to end up.
It's their wealth, or their success, or their health, or their curious, or their temporary pleasures, or their sexual fulfillment, or anything else coming to you just done.
It eventually will run dry.
And it takes longer for some of us than others are.
Some of you are in this room, and you've written from God for years, and years, and years, and years, and it took a long time for God to make you aware that there was nothing that was going to satisfy you apart from Him.
The book of Ecclesiastes is actually an experiment by King Solomon, and he did it study for those of you that know the content.
And he did this experiment where he tried to find satisfaction on it.
And he did it better than you or I will ever do it, because he had more money, more power, and more resources than you or I will ever have.
I used to teach this book to the youth group all the time, because I told my teenagers, I'd say, I know where your life is.
You want to party with your friends, and have fun, you want to experiment, you want to try all of the things.
And, like, it's going to lead to heaven and pain and difficulty.
And, like, Solomon and I, he tried it.
So, can I just tell you that he tried it, and you just agreed to, like, not try it?
I don't know how many of you have worked for, but that was my goal at this point.
And so Solomon's kind of progression, it starts with this.
Earthly pleasure will satisfy him.
And so he parties, he uses his wealth, his finances, he's successful in business, he's successful in his social life,
he's successful in his sexual life, you go read it for yourself, I'm not going to give you the context,
but the dude tried it, all right?
He tried everything.
And at the end of all of it, he has fun for a lot, but he leads to a place of disappointment and disillusionment,
and the book gets really dark, really fast.
And he says, the theme of Ecclesiastes is meaningless.
Solomon says, there's something meaningless.
It feels good for a time and to the season, but there's nothing better than to just eat and drink and be happy.
To be as happy as you.
That's this period of disillusionment, and eventually, he gets to a place where eventually he says,
there has to be something in the world that he wants on this earth.
There has to be satisfaction outside of this earth.
And so if we're going to be a people that share our faith in Jesus, as I try to understand our members close,
as people that are close to us, as far as from God, if we're going to be a people that do this on a regular basis,
it starts with us having a heart to come to close to us, as far as from God.
It starts with us realizing that eventually the well is going to run dry, but we have a source of living water that leads to eternal life.
And what more loving, compassionate, gracious thing can we do than to share that truth of love?
Not to force it down their throats, it's to lovingly invite them to experience what we have experienced in Jesus.
I saw this, you know, in a cultural moment recently.
Yes, some of these have been my animal story, most of us.
There was Fred in the NFL a few weeks ago.
He literally died on the field, and they were able to resuscitate him, and it was just like, it was eerie.
We were watching it on a lot of television.
And, and, and impulsive as post-modern and post-Christian, everyone stops being prayed.
Why?
Because somewhere deep down inside of all of us, we know that there's something further than what we can see or experience.
Okay, so we're just really good at distracting ourselves from it.
And it took that moment where everyone was exposed to death and love, where we said, man, we need something else.
Are we able to see Christ the mess that our friends and family was put on it?
We're convinced of what Jesus knew to be true.
That if they keep running back to the same well, eventually they will be supposed to meet again.
Do we have a heart for people who are close to us but far from God?
Are we convinced of their need for him?
And are we willing to be a witness to people around us?
I think most of us, including myself, have become complacent at proclaiming the kingdom of God.
And to people around us, we've gotten comfortable with a, you do your name, let me do your name, and everything will be fine.
Like, this is the same work for me, but it might not work for you.
And so, like, I don't want to step on your toes or make sense uncomfortable.
We need to align our hearts with Jesus.
He had to go to church together.
How did he?
Not out of guilt or shame, but out of passion for people.
He knew that they needed what he had to offer.
Do you, if your experience is anything like mine, I think, kind of anticipate what you're feeling.
Possibly guilt or shame for not doing it enough.
Or maybe also a real hesitancy that I'm going to ask you to do something crazy.
And you're already trying to make excuses for how you're not going to do the same.
Right?
Here's my hope.
My hope by reading this message is that there's no guilt or sin for wishing you would have done more in the past.
There's been being followed about hearing Jesus in a controlled and accessible way.
To the good news of Jesus, it doesn't seem to me.
And it is the power of God to bring salvation to people.
But the gospel doesn't change, but our methodologies have changed.
So I think some of the reasons that we don't like doing this very well is because the church and Christians, we haven't upgraded our methodology in a very long time.
We've been kind of doing the same thing the same way without realizing that culture has changed.
See, Christians recently, at least, it's my experience, that we're behind with culture, and we don't realize where culture is at, and so it's too late.
And so I think we've got to realize that culture is changing into the way that we proclaim the message of the kingdom of God through the chains.
The New Testament is full of examples, specifically Paul, in textualizing the way that he shared the gospel, depending on who was in the ring.
He understood the people that he was talking to, and he proclaimed the gospel to them differently, based on who was in the ring.
And I think that we're, when we do say it in the message of Jesus, we're sharing it with outdated methodologies.
I've got a few decades I want to watch through.
Tim Keller has a lot of really good information on this.
I'm going to send the video to everyone in the newsletters if you want to sign up, sign up, that I think will help.
I'm just going to summarize it real quick.
In the 50s and 60s, Tim Keller says that everybody had a moral foundation and a respect for the Bible.
And so that's why gospel crafts and knocking on doors and revival camp meetings, those things worked,
because there was already kind of a low-level respect and expectation and understanding others, the message of Jesus.
And so all people used to do was be reminded that they were bowing and be called back to forgiveness and the sentence.
But then in the 70s and 80s, this kind of started to go away, and signs started to make its rise, and people became intellectually skeptical about the Bible.
They started doubting this Scripture really has any power or relevancy in this modern day and age.
And so that's when apologetics started to become a bad thing, and people writing about, you know, the case for Christ and explaining exactly how historical and scientific evidence points to the Bible being true.
And then as people kind of got out of that phase, then the new thing was, well, church is outdated and boring, and that didn't impact any of my life.
I mean, these people sit on cues, and they send them out of their minds, and it's boring, and I don't see how it connects to, like, my mind-based work.
Which is when you have Rick Warren and those guys being like, okay, well, let's just make church relevant and good, and, like, let's bring some contemporary music and some lights,
and, like, let's preach practical messages that connect to people where they're at.
And this works for a lot of us.
For example, we're in a culture where there's really no moral foundation, no respect for the Bible, no cultural value in church.
A lot of you know this.
You can invite your friends to church, but they're not interested.
And so you might be the only church that they have.
And so how do we do this?
How do we serve Jesus in a culturally relevant way?
Not only do I think our methodology is outdated, but I think our message is watered down.
This one's going to hurt me, and it's going to hurt me, and it's going to hurt me, and hopefully we get through it together.
Yeah, I think, at least in the environments that I grew up in where I was taught to and made me feel guilty to go preach the gospel to my friends,
because the message that I was told to give, was boiled down to the goal of preaching to convince people that they're sinners separated from God,
getting them to feel guilty, and pray the prayer that exists nowhere in the Bible.
There is no ask Jesus into your heart for it in the Bible.
And I'm not saying that that was a totally bad way of doing it when it was done that way,
but once we've washed it down, the message.
No wonder none of us want to do it.
The gospel isn't just about where do you go, where do you die, but the gospel is about abundant life right now.
The gospel of Jesus is this, what he said with this minute and moment.
I know you're tired, and I know you're sick, broken, depressed, addicted, lonely, lost, crippled by fear, without hope.
I know you're searching for healing and satisfaction in all kinds of different areas of your life.
And I know you're getting tips of it.
I know you get things that satisfy yourself, and you're just going to be thirsty again.
But I have water that if you drink, you will never be thirsty again.
See, Jesus didn't come just to give hope for this future, although that's part of it.
He also came to give us abundant life.
Now, Christ's vision for our salvation is what he taught his disciples to pray,
that God's will would be done in our lives, in our homes, in our churches, in our communities,
as he is in heaven.
Maybe we'd be more excited about sharing the message of Jesus if this was the message of Jesus that we were sharing.
If our model has gotten more culturally relevant and our message had more power,
maybe we'll just share the message of Jesus more.
I don't know about you, but I can sign up for this kind of gospel preaching.
And honestly, guys, this message this week was a message for my own folks.
He said, I've got so bogged down in the past with bad minds, and I've allowed myself to bond into this room,
where I've just got to convince people that they're guilty and get them to pray this for them.
And it doesn't matter if it's possessed their life at all today, as long as they say these special words in a special order.
And I've done enough kindness to see people just go along with it so that I'll leave them at a point.
But it wasn't actually the meaning of Jesus.
And so no wonder we don't want to do it.
We want people to mean Jesus.
We just don't want people to, like, go through this ceremony that doesn't exist in the Bible.
This message has been a message for my own heart.
And I know what you might be thinking.
If the pastor's not doing it, why should I?
Well, my hope is that we will both touch a vision this morning to a fresh and compelling way to hear this true message of Jesus
that isn't just about where you go when you've done this, but about an abundant life in life.
About how the world is being done in our lives, in our homes, in our community, in our church, as it is in heaven.
So putting this message is great for you into a scale that I'll let fall down in our lives, in our lives, in our lives, in our lives.
You and all have been called to be Christ witnesses, to neighbors, to family members, like colleagues, and friends,
and we can't let out their methodologies or water down message, not just out of the way.
So, what's the alternative?
What's the solution?
And I'll summarize it this way, and my main point to this whole topic is that if we're going to hear the gospel
and the methodology that works for our culture and the message that isn't narrowed down,
we're called to live a compelling life and tell a compelling story.
Live a compelling life.
Tell a compelling story.
This is what Jesus does to the Semaître and woman.
This is what the early church does.
This is what Paul does when he says, follow me as I follow Christ.
That message, that verse, he's just freaking out.
I'm like, who does Paul think he is?
Follow me.
We're supposed to follow Jesus.
Don't follow him.
You follow Jesus.
Or then I convince myself, like, well, he's an apostle.
He's an apostle, so he can say that.
No, the more that I think about it, the more I realize that this invitation, that statement,
is Christian discipleship.
We're called to follow Jesus in a compelling way.
So we're called to be obedient to the teachings of Jesus in such a way that we can look at
our neighbors, our co-workers, our friends, and we can say, come along.
Follow me as I follow Jesus.
And maybe we're not doing that because deep down in our head, we really don't want to
follow Jesus as much as we say we do.
I think, I think most of us, we want to, but we make it to do this.
And the reason we're not sharing our faith in Jesus is because we know our life's not compelling
because we've been spending most of our time making excuses.
But once you got real serious about following Jesus, about doing the things that Jesus did,
about loving people unconditionally, about stepping into the lives of the poor, the powerless,
and the persecuted, about going to our community and serving Jesus.
We should be living compelling lives and telling a compelling story.
The Samaritan woman seems so surprised by Jesus.
Grace, my friend.
This woman was surprised.
For Jesus, he doesn't have anything to do with Samaritan woman.
She said to you, if you're a Jew, and I'm a Samaritan woman, why are you asking me for a drink?
This is what it looks like to live a compelling life.
Are we living a life that our friends, family members, photographers, and neighbors, like,
look at us like, that's interesting.
Why are you, you're not judging, you're a Christian, you're not judging me.
I just told you that I'm sleeping in your arms, right, and judging you.
I just told you that I've got a drug problem.
Why are you condemning me?
I'll be pushing me off of your life.
This is what Christians are supposed to do, right?
What if we live a different way?
What if we live people, the way that Jesus loved people?
He loved this woman so much, he took past cultural, religious norms.
He didn't care about how his actions might be perceived, because he was compelled to have
a conversation with this woman about the living water that he had to do.
What if I tell a compelling story of both of us living a compelling life?
I heard one pastor say it this way, he said, be the first Christians that your friends like.
Right?
I was like, that's so good.
He said, be the first Christian that your friends like.
And that doesn't mean to compromise truth.
It doesn't mean to try to blend in and fit in and be cool.
And that's my MO, right?
Like, I'm the pastor that wants to be cool.
I'm the one that wants to tell people on that pastor, and they're like, no way.
And it comes from a good heart, but we can't water down the message of Jesus.
But we love in the midst.
We don't expect people who aren't following Jesus to live like they're following you.
Daniel was incredible.
It's like, I'm so far behind my notes.
I mean, if you get bored, just read.
Go to the book of Daniel.
And Daniel is hostile to using Babylon.
And Babylon is a culture that was totally opposed to the culture of the Jews.
And they were persecuting the Jews.
And Daniel was essentially a slave.
He lived his whole life in Babylon, never compromising the slave.
And at the end, he's, like, elevated to, like, a high governmental position.
He's, like, super old.
And they're still reaching out for Daniel for a life, for wisdom.
Because he lived a radical life.
He lived a compelling life.
And that compelling life brought him opportunities to have conversations, to tell people a compelling story.
Notice the story that Jesus tells this woman.
It's not untractical.
It's not totally disconnected from her reality.
Jesus knows the pain point in this woman's life.
He says, go get your husband.
This woman's pain point was relationships.
Right?
Like, he had gone back to the well of relationships five, now going on six times.
He says, that's right.
You don't have a husband.
You've had five husbands.
And now you're living with a guy that's not your husband.
And Jesus isn't doing this.
To be judgmental or to have shame or guilt on this woman.
He's doing it to sell her that she hasn't been able to satisfy the choice that she has.
We need to tell compelling stories that connect to people's actual lives.
We need to be good enough friends where we know where people are struggling.
We know where people are hurting.
And we can offer Jesus as the solution to their problem.
Because Jesus is the solution to their conflict.
And every other solution will leave them satisfied to their time but a whole story will drown out.
Jesus is just bringing an eternal life, bubbling up a well that he never remains.
Drone.
There's a compelling story of grace and forgiveness of Jesus' life for us.
We should live that out and steal it with others.
Friends, a woman does probably what your friends are going to do when you step out in space and do this.
She, like, lures them into a theological debate.
She doesn't want to talk about the actual issues in her life.
She's like, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, you're right.
You must be a prophet.
That's cool, but, like, you guys say that we don't worship God, right?
And she's, like, lures them into this theological debate.
But Jesus takes the debate.
He engages her in the conversation.
And then he offers himself as a sleuth in verse 26.
She says, I know a Messiah is coming.
And he says, I am in the sea.
Notice the woman's response.
Verse 28.
The woman left the water dry beside the well and ran back to the village to tell everyone.
She's immediately better at preaching the gospel when you don't know how to be taught.
And she's not even a father of Jesus yet.
This is the power of a compelling life and a compelling story.
Start from your own story.
Tell your friends of the times when you were trapped in addiction.
When your heart was hard, when you were lost and without hope.
When you got to the end of all the pleasures of this life and your well was still dried up.
And tell them of the way that Jesus met you in your brokenness, in your sin, in your guilt, in your unloved, in your unforgiveness.
Whatever it was for you, define them for them.
Pull out the crimson plan that Jesus met you in and tell them how Jesus was the answer to that problem.
You don't have to know all the answers to all the questions.
You just have to live a compelling life and tell a compelling story.
I love how Brace Pascal puts it.
He's an old, dead, white guy.
So, this is not truth that I'm just making up.
It says, bring people to a place where they wish Christianity was true and then show them it's true.
This is living a compelling life.
This is telling a compelling story.
Live in such a way that people with Christianity were true.
And then show them it's true.
Oh, let's get really practical.
Kelly, you can come on and tell me when I told you.
I'm still quite on.
It's okay.
It'll work out.
First step, if we're going to live a compelling life, tell a compelling story, if we're going to be a people who get serious about sharing our faith with people who are close to us but far from God,
which is this.
Identify and pray.
Write down the names of people that are close to you but far from God and begin to pray that God will be going to work in their lives and give you opportunities to hear them.
It's not your job to save people.
God's in the business of saving people.
When you partner with them, when you come alongside people that he's already working in their lives, let's begin to pray for it.
Ask God to work in people's lives.
Be intentional.
When you're out and about in the community, I did this the other day.
I was just like walking through mountains and praying that God is in his eyes and ears to hear what he's doing.
Be intentional when you're out and about.
Pray that God might put somewhere in your place that he is drawing himself.
Secondly, live a compelling life.
Be a great friend.
A great co-worker.
A family member.
Love people unconditionally without strings attached.
You yourself drive close to Jesus.
Be obedient to him.
When you're actually obeying and seeing how much abundant life rocks,
you're more compelled to say, come with me.
Let's go do this thing together.
Grow close to Jesus.
Be conformed into him.
Because it's his enemy.
And tell us who tell us where it goes.
We have to preach the gospel.
We have to use words.
We have to tell people about Jesus.
We can't just hope that they fall into Jesus because we're in a way.
Look for good opportunities to tell people what God is doing in your life and invite them to come along.
Be a friend.
Get to know the struggles in your friends on those.
Ask spiritual questions and offer Jesus as a solution to their struggle.
And then lastly, pray again and trust God.
You're only responsible for feeling the message.
You're not responsible for the results.
And so many of us grew up in the same culture that I grew up in.
We felt guilty for not doing it enough, for not doing it well enough.
Our responsibility is to come alongside what God is already doing.
In Romans 1, 16, he said, God is full of power.
It's not how good you feel.
And here's the deal.
God is already doing things in people's lives.
And you never know how you might be a part of what God is doing.
I love what 1 Corinthians 3 says.
Also, it's not important if he does the cleansing or he does the watering.
What's important is that God makes the seed grow.
God does it.
But the one who plants and the one who waters, we all work together with the same quickness.
And both of us will be rewarded for our own hard work.
We just look like the team.
We're going to be coming on here.
We invite people to come on here.
We share a compelling story.
And who knows what God might do?
And who knows how God might use one little thing that you did in a long line of 15 other things that you did to 15 other people?
I've got a test.
January 17th, this year, from my pastor in Pennsylvania.
I think I have a picture.
It's really cute.
Yeah, it's a good name.
This is Adam Blue.
And he says, he said,
Hey, bro, tonight I got to lead our friend Nicole to Christ at our dining room table after this pastor of Discovery Bible study.
It was really cool to hear her talk about her journey and how the feeling that he preached in 2019 and the first and second of them
was the thing that began to open her on this issue.
You, Plano, tons of people have wandered in all these four years.
Super grateful for you.
I hope you're in phase.
Here's what my situation is.
That woman's journey started four years ago.
I have one little thing.
I preach to them.
I get paid to do that.
I'm not trying to pat myself on the back here.
I have to.
My point is this.
You never know how one conversation, one act of kindness in the name of Jesus,
one stepping out of faith to talk to your friends about what Jesus is saying in your life,
might be used in a long string of things that God is using to bring to grow.
Jesus always follows, the harvest is great.
It's a statement of fact.
It's not, it might be great if you do the right things.
The harvest is great.
Jesus is drawing people to himself, but the workers are here.
So pray to the Lord who is in charge of the harvest.
And I'm not trying to respond to more workers than the person.
He's not praying for more harvest.
The harvest is already great.
It's praying for more workers.
That means if we go, we can be assured that the harvest will come with us.
It is great.
There's a great harvest outside these walls.
In our neighborhoods, workplaces, community parks, family get-togethers, grocery stores, and more.
May we partner with what God is already doing.
May we be faithful to plants and water and spit back and watch them produce the growth.
Speak people who live compelling lives, compelling stories.
In light of communion this morning, there should be a card somewhere near you.
This is something that I'll put together just to start to get the wheels coming about what it might look like to hear a compelling story from your own life.
Put some prompts in there for you to think about.
What were the tensing points in your life when Jesus drew you to himself?
What were the areas where you kept going back to the same well over and over and over again and it wasn't satisfying?
We begin to kind of just summarize that story out so that you can internalize it.
It's part of your story.
The gospel message that you proclaim to your friends is compelling.
It's not guilt-driven.
If you're watching online, obviously you don't have the cards.
There's an app called God Tools put on by Alpha and it has a very similar thing on the front screen of those things that you don't like that and check it out.
And if you're here and you're not a follower of Jesus, this message was really mostly not for you.
But here's where it is for you.
The world is all run down.
You probably want to sit at one point or another and maybe you found a new glass, a new colored receipt that is working for you now, but eventually it's going to run down to you.
So I believe God's brought me here today to tell you that wisdom is a source of a tremendous love.
That you submit your life to the Lordship and leadership doesn't make every bad thing in your life go away.
It means the things you submit to us.
And you consider becoming a follower of Jesus, as I was going on this morning.
And lastly, this is a, this is an organizationally driven deep planting.
There's a, there's a few really great questions that are geared towards people who don't know Jesus.
Right important and alpha are a little bit, my two favorites.
If you have a, if you have a burning kind of thing to create space for people to, to kind of experience, answer the questions, I would love for all sorts of stuff that I can do.
So just, I'm just drawing it up here.
Do it all.
If that's you, I'd love to talk to you more about it.
And I'm digging in with, not learning in this sort of, start this process.
And then I'm going to come up and, and soon as God, there's a blessing.
Let's begin to write down names of people that are close to us before us.
And God, let's begin to write down our stories and place for how God might use us to partner in his helpers.
I think that's got some closing signs.
God, let's begin to write down names of people that are close to us.
Let's begin to write down names of people that are close to us.